Hello everyone, we are
We are the Rainbow Conquistadors.
Yes, I'm Ao Iwata
Yes, I'm Marina Kumamoto
Yes, I'm Riko Shimizu
Yes, I'm Karin Mataha
Well, this time we came to Kagoshima Prefecture
Yay!
I'm so happy! Look at this!
Amazing!
So beautiful So beautiful
So, as many of you have probably seen in the video, we had a rice karuta tournament in March, and Mr. Shimizu and Ms. Kumamoto won the tournament.
In March, we held a rice karuta championship, and the winners, Shimizu and Kumamoto, played rice karuta against elementary school students from Kagoshima prefecture.
They came to Kagoshima to play rice karuta against elementary school students from Kagoshima prefecture.
Hey!
What is it?
Did Mr. Matoba win?
Oh, no...
Karin didn't win...
She was so good at the rice karuta championship, with her commentary and rice commercials.
What was that all about?
This time, she will be participating as a special commentator!
Commentator
I look forward to working with you.
My name is Matoba, and I am a commentator.
And now, for the final installment of the rice karuta series, I'd like to introduce you to the four of us.
Let's begin with the information about the school system that we will be visiting this time.
Yes, this time we will be visiting a 5th grade class at Nakayama Elementary School in Kagoshima City.
There are six fifth grade classes, 246 students.
246 students, that's a lot!
They have already held a preliminary competition to decide the representative of each class in advance.
So, a total of 12 students will be competing against each other.
That's over 200 students.
That's right.
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
And the whole 5th grade will be there to watch the competition.And, to our surprise, all the 5th graders will be watching the match.
I heard that all the 5th graders will be watching the match.
That's a lot of people.
Only 426 students will be watching.
I have to show them my best.
Well, then... what's your motivation?
After all, I'm more than a year older than you.
I'm an elementary school student.
An elementary schooler.
As expected, we can't lose.
I'm determined to win.
You're the best of 246.
I'm shaking now when I hear that.
We're the top of the second marriage.
We're the pinnacle of the competition, so we're going to fight hard and win.
Well then, let's all go to Nakayama Elementary School.
Oh!
Thank you for watching.
Thank you for waiting.
Here you go.
Seino
Hi, Nee-chan.
Hello!
Hello, everyone!
Hello everyone!
Hello.
We are Rainbow Conchissadors!
Nice to meet you!
Did you have a good time at school?
I had a great time!
I would like to ask a question to all of you energetic junior high and third grade elementary school students.
What is your favorite class?
I like social studies.
Social studies?
What is your current social studies class?
Right now, I'm learning about life in the cold lands.I'm living in a cold land right now.
Living.
I see. I see.
Can I ask you the next question?
What's your favorite school lunch?
I like white rice.
That's great.
White rice?
Do you get second helpings?
Yes, I do.
How did you like playing rice karuta?
It was good to know about many kinds of rice and their characteristics.
Great!
Thank you three for answering the questions.
Applause
Now, I would have liked to ask you all more questions.
I'm going to have you play rice karuta with us now!
Yay!
Let's play rice karuta!
So this time, we will play rice karuta and have a quiz here at Nakayama Elementary School!
In the first round of the rice karuta game, the Nijikon team will be playing against me, Shimizu, and Marina, and the Nakayama Elementary School team will be playing against 6 players!
The winner will be the team with 5 cards!
Let's start the first round!
Let's start!
Glossy and rich
Yes, what is the picture?
Yumemi ribbon
Correct!
Amazing!
Now, on to the next one.
Refreshing on the palate
Quick!
Refreshing on the palate with just the right amount of chewinessRefreshing on the palate with just the right amount of crunchiness
Stickiness Hiroshima Prefecture Autumn Color Manchurian
Correct!
That's great!
We were the second to finish!
Now, on to the next one.
Large and firm
Fast
tender, white and blue, with a full flavor
Three pieces taken by one person!
A fine piece of history.
Strong!
And now we take
The best of the best.
Amazing!
That's really strong.
Very strong
Fresh and sweet.
It's strong, but...
You can taste the fresh sweetness and stickiness.
Gunma Tonekirari
Correct answer
Amazing.
Eh, I can't help it a little bit without getting one piece each.
The students were so overwhelmingly strong that the game seemed to end without getting even a single card, so the rules were suddenly changed.
The rule was changed to "10 cards players".
And then, the brains of Nijikon, Yamato Ao, joined the skeet.
Yamato Ao joins the game!
Will the Nijikon team be able to show their maturity?
Let's see the rest of the game!
A good balance of whiteness, stickiness, and hardness
Ginga no Shizuku from Iwate Prefecture
I studied so hard!
Now, what did you get?
Ginga no Shizuku
Correct answerCorrect
I'm sorry to hear that
Followed by
Strong stickiness and !
Sticky texture! The grains are large and plump, full of sweetness and flavor!
As good as Kagoshima's Akiho!
As it should be!
That's Kagoshima!
Next
Fragrant, sweet and umami spreading softly
Toyama Prefecture
Correct!
Three more to go!
Three more are not good!
Let's go!
Kirakira Tsuyayako
I know what this is!
Just the right amount of stickiness and sweetness.
and sweetness of shigakegakemon
Suikagami
Correct answer
You can't beat it, even with reflexes
Beautiful white
fast
Wakayaba
Oh no!
I can't understand it! Princess!
That's right!
Oh, no!
The grains are firm! Sticky even when cold!
Tough in the heat! Fukuoka Prefecture!
How are you doing in Fukuoka?
Fukuoka is fine!
I'm so happy! Yay!
Misery!
I'm happy!Glad!!!
Unhappy!
Well, I got one of the secondary high team!
I'm so happy!
Here we go!
Sweetness and stickiness
Texture with starry twinkling splendor
Hot linken, star gramai. Correct.
So, let's count them!
How about you, Nakayama Elementary School?
10!
And the Mizuko team?
One!
So, the Nakayama Elementary School team wins!
Aren't they too strong?
They want more!
Want to play more?
So, overtime!
The Nakadan Elementary School team will switch their 6 representatives.
The winner will be determined by three cards.
Everybody ready to cheer?
Okay.
Let's go.
Start of the second round.
Well balanced
Aroma and Tenacity! Beautiful white and glossy!
Shimane Prefecture Kinumusume Sekai!
The grains are plump and light
It has sweetness and is deep and rich.
Kashiwagi Prefecture Fukumaru
Correct answer!
Now, there is only one piece left for the Toyama Elementary School team!
A balance of flavor, stickiness, and sweetness, with an elegant aroma.
Akita Prefecture, Akita Komachi!
Wow!Wow!
Sekai!
So, a straight run for the junior high school school team!
How was it fighting 2-second teams?
It was great!
Oh my god, I was only going to get the Wakayama team.
But I was so depressed that they took it.
I couldn't do it anymore, really.
It was amazing!
He was so strong.
That was great.
Next up was a game called "KENSEI API Game"!
This is a game in which you guess the prefecture based on the main industries written on the rice karuta card.
The winner is determined by how many questions you can answer within the time limit of one minute.
Are you all ready?
Whoo-hoo!
How are you doing?
Almost there.
It's in!
Yes, it's in!
Well, let's go while we still can!
Let's get started!
Yes!
This prefecture's industry is peaches.
Here you go!
Shu-shu-shu!
Tsuru-murasuki
Fukuoka Prefecture
No, sir.
string beans
Fukuoka
Ding-dong!
Followed by
Melon
Yes, sir.Yes
Fukuoka Prefecture
Ding-dong!
Continue...
Cabbage
FUKUOKA
Hold on!
Stop!
No, sir!
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Yes! Come on!
Ding-dong!
Hold on!
konnyaku imo
Yes, sir.
Let's see...
Ibaraki Prefecture
Bubu
Edamame Cabbage
Yes
Ding-dong!
Followed by
Strawberries!
Yes!
Turn around!
Ding-dong!
Yes!
Okay, here's the tally!
One, two, three, four, five!
That took 12 seconds!
That's good, that's good, that's good!
Once every 12 seconds!
That's fast!
That's fast! You did it, you did it, you did it! Nice, nice!Quick, quick, quick! Good job, good job! Nice, nice!
Next, the Nijikon team will take on the challenge!
If you can answer at least 5 questions, you win!
The Nijikon team is off to a good start!
What is the main industry of this prefecture?
Ume!
Yes!
Wakayama!
Correct!
Next, Muscat!
Divergence!
Yes!
Asashi.
No, sir.
Muscat
Cut.
L'Argenteu.
Where was it?
To the Earth Heavenly Garden.
Pass, pass, pass.
Pass, pass, pass! Pass, pass, pass, pass!
Let's continue.
Lettuce
Yes, sir.
Haragamon
Correct!
Followed by
Ayu
Yes, sir.
Correct!
Next, Blueberry
Yes!
Tokyo!
Correct!
LOL!
Next,Followed by,
Racka sei!
Yes!
Number one!
Correct!
Laughs.
That's great!
LOL!
Next,
Taro, green onion
Yes!
Oh!
Correct!
Next,
Maki!
Correct!
LOL!
Next,
Maki!
LOL!
And then the shijimi grapes!
Aaaaah!
Oh, my gosh!
I'm so excited!
Well, I'll make an announcement!
Nijikon Team
One card
2 cards
Three.
4 cards
5 sheets
6 cards
Nijikon team wins
177th Inoue joint player win177th Inoue Co.
traffic jam challenge
So we will have a 30-second overtime game!
Intermediate elementary school team, let's go!
All right, let's get started!
The main industry of this prefecture is firefly squid!
Yes! Toyama Prefecture!
Correct!
Next, the summer season and the summer year
knife
Yes, sir.
Ah, Heisei Gen
Ah, no
Yes, Gifu
Correct
Oh.
Okay, here we go.
This is seaweed.
Yes, sir.
Oh, department store
Correct.
Yes, sir.
Oh!
Rock, paper, scissors
Ooh.
You have 30 seconds.
Okay, 30 seconds. The Nakayama Elementary School team...
One, two, three.
Wow, you're so well-prepared.
Secondary school team, let's go!
Let's go!
The main industry of this prefecture is skipjack.
That's great!
Next, Ookami beef, Mishima, Senbei...Continue: Ookamigyu, Mishima, 1,000 sheets
Continue - Rakujyo - 1,000 pieces
Followed by Cherry blossoms - 1,000 pieces
Followed by 4 olives and garlic
I don't know!
Where is it?
Mikiko's team, one, two, three, four...
There!
The Mijikon team wins!
Yay!
Maybe we won't lose big.
Maybe we won't lose big enough to die.
How was the fight?
I knew the middle schoolers were too strong.
We were all so excited.
But, you know, we're not going to lose. We're desperate.
How was the junior high?
They were so strong!
Were you nervous? Did you have fun?
Oh, my God!
It was a lot of fun!
Can you tell me what you thought?
It was difficult, but everyone was so strong, so it was a lot of fun!
You can't lose, you can't lose.
You're so strong.
I saw that you and many other people were strong in karuta.
I want to tell them.
Will you tell them?
I think I got it.
Okay, here's the karuta.
There were a lot of questions that I couldn't answer.
I thought I should learn a little more.
Cool! You had a good spirit.
You guys were really strong.
Will you continue to play rice karuta?
Yeah! I'd love to!Yeah! I'm so happy!
Well, that's it for the rice karuta showdown!
Yay!
Finally, we would like to interview the teacher who has been watching over the rice karuta for a day!
Teacher, how was today's rice karuta?
The kids were really interested in rice,
We had a very hot qualifying round until today.
Wow! I wish I could have seen that.
I wish I could have seen it!
Some of them were so happy to participate and some of them were in tears,
I think it was a great experience.
Our area here in Chunan High School is now a residential area,
The rice fields have been cultivated here for more than 30 years,
Local people come here to teach us how to grow rice.
The local people come here to teach us how to grow rice,
We hope that through growing rice with the children, they will learn about the difficulties of rice farming and the joys of making rice,
We want them to have an interest in agriculture and to eat rice with gratitude,
I am now able to raise children who are interested in agriculture and who are grateful for the rice they eat,
It was a very good experience for me. Thank you very much.
I was very happy!
So, thank you very much for today!
Thank you very much!
Thank you very much, Nakayama Elementary School students!
For the second con, we are visiting Karen Kagoshima in Kagoshima City.
Yes, so we have brought you three installments of the
Rice Caltta series,
The winner of this series will receive rice from all over Japan
We promised to give away rice from all over Japan and good food from Kagoshima to the winner,
We are preparing it today!
Yay!
So, Karin-senpai, please!
Yes, the feast this time is run by JA Kagoshima Keizairen (Japan Agricultural Cooperatives Association),
This time, we are going to have a special dish at Karen's Kagoshima branch, which is run by JA Kagoshima Keizairen,
Kagoshima Kurobuta pork shabu shabu shabu and seiro-mushi!
And the rice is Kagoshima-grown autumn green rice!
Here is a map of the food,So, I have a food taste map here,
Autumn Ohonami is here!
Just the right balance!
Just the right amount of stickiness and sweetness,
Right in the right place, right?
This is the place!
Autumn Ohonami with Kurobuta pork shabu shabu shabu,
Seiro-mushi, what a lot of food!
Yay!
This way!
Yes, we have prepared it,
Do you guys notice anything strange?
No, I thought so.
Something, something, something.
Something, something.
I'm a little short. Sorry.
Yes, it is. That's right.
This time, we suddenly had four participants,
We don't have enough for the first person.
Okay, Karin-senpai.
Thank you, Karin-senpai.
A game of guessing the masterpieces in a hurry!
This game is to guess the famous picture from the prefectures written on the rice karuta.
The winner is the player who guesses 2 questions.
Let's start the guessing game!
Yes, let's start!
Iwate Prefecture
Is it me?
Ginga no Shizuku
Correct answer
Hiroshima Prefecture
Aki-Roma
That's it!
I knew it!
Contrast knowledge is too much!
I'm falling forward.It's the front end.
2 Guilickel.
Wait.
God of Musubi
I'm hit!
I'm out.
I'm out!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Please, please, please
Let's do our best, Karin!
Let's do it one question at a time.
Let's do one question.
Goyamaken.
What was it?
I don't know.
Oh, yeah.
Isn't it bad?
It's the easiest to understand.
Yes, my first thought.
Oh, shit.
Question.
Shiga Prefecture.
Correct answer
Water mirror
Ah! There!
[Correct answer]
Yes!
Yeah!
Two people just lost.
[QUESTION]
NIIGATA Prefecture
[Correct answer]
Shinnosuke.Shinnosuke
Oh!
We did it!
I'm not gonna let you win!
You said it yourself.
You said that?
Um, can I make one excuse?
I failed the first round of the rice hunt, didn't I?
Marina, I just got two questions.
I got it, I got it.
Two. Two.
No way!
What's your boyfriend's score right now?
Zero!
Oh no! You ate!
So here's your reward!
The winners of the rice picking reward were
Ao, Marina, and Simi!
Yay!
I won't eat it!
Now, please join hands together.
Let's eat!
Bon appétit!
I'm so happy.
The fresh bugs smell so good!
Why am I the closest to raw bugs?
I think I'll start with the rice.
Akihonahana
Bon appétit!
They're so sparkly.
You really sparkle, don't you?
It shines.
Bon appétit.Bon appétit!
Why are you looking at me first?
Delicious!
The grains are so big and the flavor is so concentrated in them.
It's so delicious that you could eat several bowls of rice alone!
I bet it would be even better with meat!
It's delicious!
Shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi-shabi
Soon
Sweet
Looks delicious
Maybe I'll go get the rice cooker.
You want to take this?
With this, you can sip it.
Bon appétit.
Excuse me.
Looks delicious.
I'm gonna go check it out.
How is it? How's the ssha-ssha-ssha?
Oh, my God, it melts in your mouth.
It just melts in your mouth.
It's lighter than I expected.
But you can really taste the sweetness of the fat.
It's delicious!
It's so tender.
I'll have a drink with it.
Oh, no, that's okay.
With Iyashi.
How is it?
Sounds good.
He's got a nice voice.
It sounds good.
I'll play it for you.
Sounds good.Sounds good.
Sounds delicious.
The pork is laid on top of the bean sprouts.
When eaten together, it's light and refreshing
and the fat is nice and comforting.
Delicious!
I hope you like it!
It's also great to eat together!
Delicious!
I'm so happy.
You?
This is it.
This? Did you come?
This is what I came for.
I'm supposed to be here for this, too.
That's not right.
No, you're not.
You're a commentator.
Well, how did you like the rice karuta that you have learned through the three sessions?
First of all, the main purpose of my visit to Kagoshima.
Winning?
Yes, the game.
As I have said many times, they were stronger than I imagined.
They were really strong.
It was great, wasn't it?
It was great.
You know what really impressed me the most?
We were all able to answer so many questions.
They were like, "You must have studied a lot.
When I asked him about that long time ago, he said, "It's not that I studied...
They said it was because we were all playing together during recess on a rainy day.
I knew it, rice karuta is like that.
When you're studying, you get a bit excited, don't you?
I thought it was a great way to learn while having fun.
I thought it would be great if people could learn how to eat rice and learn about the various charms of rice.
We also discussed problems in the car while we were on the road.We used to solve each other's problems in the car or on the road, right?
It was fun, wasn't it?
I want to do it more.
I want to.
I was just wondering...
What is this?
You should wave to it.
It's too familiar.
Did you notice?
You noticed.
I noticed it.
When I was in elementary school, elementary school.
You were surrounded.
Surrounded me like crazy.
It was like a really popular content.
They cheered us up, didn't they?
That's great.
He was like, "Thank you," and when he was holding it for the kids...
They were like, "Thank you," and they squirted it on me.
It was a gift from the kids.
Thank you for coming, ladies and gentlemen.
Not for me, for all of you.
Good luck, rainbow!
I was really happy, so I just put it on.
I put this on.
You really touched me with your kindness.
It was fun, wasn't it?
It was fun.
Yes, so I hope you all had a good time.
You can compare rice from all over the country.
I hope you will enjoy Japanese rice more and more.
I hope you will enjoy Japanese rice even more!
Thank you very much!
That's all for us
Rainbow Kankistadam.
Thank you very much.Thank you very much.
Let's eat then.
Let's eat.
Let's continue.
Let's eat!
I bet it tastes good with rice.
It might get dirty.
Yes, if you eat it.
The commentator looks so sad.
Vegetables are delicious too!
This concludes our three-part rice karuta series!
How did you all like it?
Have you become more interested in rice?
Let's support Japanese rice more and more with us!
Please subscribe to our channel!